Curriculum-Vitae-Resume

Contact Information

Name: Robert (Bob) Kranson

Location: Metro Detroit Area

Email: devopsbob@outlook.com

Website link: https://devopsbob.github.io/Curriculum-Vitae-Resume

Objective

I manipulate new and existing technologies to implement software frameworks that deliver secure, highly-testable business applications.

Summary

As a technical architect, I have expertise in various areas, including SAFe Agile methodology, DevSecOps tools, NodeJS/JavaScript, and Java Enterprise Edition. Additionally, I have advanced experience in designing platforms for hardware and software, with a focus on multi-cloud, multi-tiered, distributed, or containerized implementations. I'm also well-versed in release pipeline and delivery technologies, utilizing Azure DevOps or Jenkins and GitHub source management.

- Content Management: Adobe Experience Manager, IBM Content Navigator, IBM Content Platform Engine
- Java Technologies: SpringBoot, Java Persistence Architectures (JPA), Java Enterprise Edition implementations
- Deployments: Cloud Image Containers and Registries, Nexus, JFrog, Docker, Java, NodeJS, JBoss, WebSphere Network
- Database Technologies: Oracle database tuning, MySQL database tuning, MS-SQL database
- Markup Languages: XML, XSLT, HTML

Roles

- Release Engineer
- Business Analyst
- DevSecOps Engineer / Technical Lead
- Technology Coach / Agile Scrum Master

Solutions

- Big Data ETL/Cloud Integrations Requirements and Modelling
- Agile Backlog Management: AzureDevOps, CA-Rally, JIRA
- DevOps Tools Artisan, Secure Configuration Integrations

Skills

- Data: S3, RedShift, Databricks, Excel, Scala
- Integration: Azure, Jenkins, OpenShift, Dynatrace, Maven, Gradle, Groovy scripting
- Collaboration: Visio, MS Teams/O365, WebEx Teams, BlueScape, BluePrint/Storyteller
- Configuration as Code: K8s, YAML, Docker/Podman, Image Registry
- Secure Platforms: SSL Administration, OAuth2, SSO, HashiCorp Vault

Key Engagements

Industry	Role	Activities
Major Utility	Release Engineer	Develop Azure pipelines, supporting Wiki, ReactJS troubleshooting, deployment hardening, Scrum Master and Business analyst.
Major Healthcare	Business Analyst	Big data extract, transform, load, audit, modeling aid and functional reporting requirements gathering within agile team.
Major Finance	DevOps Engineer	Convert Cloud66 deployment mechanism for Ruby on Rails application to Azure DevOps pipelines.
Major Technology	Trainer / Technical Architect	Technical interviewing, coaching and team building to enable recent career changing technical bootcamp graduates.
Major Healthcare	DevOps Engineer	Develop prototypes and proofs to support technology migration and shift in-progress at client site.

Industry	Role	Activities
Major Manufacturing	AEM DevOps Engineer	Configuration as code site management across multiple properties and technology implementations.
Major Automotive	DevOps Agile Coach	Promoted full-stack cloud-foundry technologies and tools to affect Development Operations (DevSecOps) methodologies implementation with complex partner and third-party integrations.
Major Banking	Installation Architect	Designed, install, and configured overall system architecture. Coordinated the work across multiple integration teams.
Major Insurance	Technical Architect	Architect and technical lead for integration project. Managed secure configuration integration and client support team training on platform to transition developed BPM solution.
Major Automotive	Integration Architect	Installed and configured a multi-server, clustered WebSphere Server environment. Documented run-book architecture and trained client administrators. Provided advanced migration troubleshooting support.

Education

- Bachelor of Science, Central Michigan University 2014
- Associate of Arts, Macomb Community College 1995
- Business Data Processing, Warren Career Preparation Center 1990
- Diploma, Warren High School 1990

Professional Training and Certifications

- Scaled Agile, Certified SAFe 5 Scrum Master, January 2023
- Scaled Agile, Certified SAFe 5 Agilist, January 2023
- Udemy, Managing Change: Learn to Thrive Through Change, August 2021
- Udemy, Mastering Collaboration: Work together for the best results, June 2021
- Udemy, The Practical BPMN 2.0 Master Class, July 2021
- Scrum Alliance, Scrum Foundations, September 2019
- Scrum Alliance, Certified Scrum Master, August 2017

Adobe, Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) 6.1 Certifications (multiple), 2017

Professional / Community Involvement

- Perficient, Bright Paths Program, 2021 thru 2022
- Perficient, Detroit Foundry Team, 2021
- Ford Motor Company, Digital Worker Expert, November 2017
- The Parade Company, Americas Thanksgiving Day Parade (Detroit), 10+ years
- The Parade Company, Super Bowl XL Volunteer, February 2006
- Wheatland Music Organization, Festival Volunteer, 20+ years
- Detroit Grand Prix Association, Track Services Volunteer, 7+ years
- Ford Motor Company, CORL/CORL-NG, 2010
- Ford Motor Company, Global Study Process Allocation System (GSPAS 2.1 Release), 1999
- I-Speak Personality Assessment: Favored conditions Primary=Sensor, Backup=Intuitor; Stress conditions - Primary=(equal)Sensor and Thinker, Backup=(equal) Intuitor and Feeler

Experience

Perficient: Technical Architect: March 2016-Present

Perficient Client - Major Utility: Release Engineer: Apr-2023-Sept-2023

Azure infrastructure-as-code using Bicep templates to support solution development and delivery using Azure LogicApps, ReactJS, ArcGIS Enterprise, and CosmosDB.

Responsibilities

- Business roles Scrum Master, Business Analyst
- Technology roles Infrastructure Lead, Release Engineer, Site Reliability Engineer
- Workflow tools Azure DevOps, SharePoint, Office365

Business/Technology Value

- Utilize latest version of ArcGIS Enterprise
- Utilize Azure Cloud hosting
- Internet of Things (IOT) Geographical analysis of device health and troubleshootin

Perficient Client - Major Healthcare: Business Analyst: Oct-2022-Mar-2023

Business analyst assisting big data analytics modelling and data movement between multiple vendor data stores.

Responsibilities

- Technology roles Visio, MS-SQL, RedShift, Postgres, Databricks interface management
- Workflow tools SharePoint linked JIRA requirements and card creation

Business/Technology Value

Assist client and team to facilitate and define gathering requirements which influence:

- Infrastructure cost savings through big data hosting platform shift
- Long term architectural data governance alignment considered during shift
- Compliance to business-controlled access utilization while reconciling validated data
- Improved access to managed operational cost and performance growth on updated platform

Perficient Client - Major Finance : DevOps Engineer : Jan-2022-May-2022

Convert Cloud66 deployment mechanism for Ruby on Rails application to Azure DevOps pipelines.

Perficient Client - Perficient: BrightPaths 2 Technical Trainer: Jan-2021-Dec-2021

Perficient Client - Major Healthcare: DevOps Engineer: Jul-2021-Sept-2021

Perficient Client - Perficient : BrightPaths 1 Technical Trainer : Apr-2020-Jan-2021

Perficient Client - Major Manufacturing: AEM DevOps Engineer: Oct-2020-Jan-2021

Perficient Client - Major Manufacturing: DevOps Agile Coach: Apr-2016-Jan-2020

Pyramid Solutions: Senior Software Engineer: August 2013-March 2016

HBM Prenscia (formerly HBM Inc. / nCode International) : *Applications Specialist* : February 2005-August 2013

Compuware Corporation: Customer Support Representative: November 1993-November 2004

Compuware Product - OptimalJ: Technical Support Analyst: 2003-2004

Compuware Product - OptimalJ : Customer Service Representative : 2002-2003

Compuware Product - UNIFACE : Senior Technical Support Analyst : 2000-2002

Compuware Client - Ford Motor Company: Technical Specialist: 1995-1999

Wayne State University: Professional Technician: September 2003-April 2004